Guide to the Alexander Jackson Davis Architectural Drawing Collection 1827-1884 PR 16
New-York Historical Society
- Lyon, Samuel E. Cottage (Item 133 verso)
  later moved to 7 Lyon Place, rear addition 1847; gardener's house 1851; demolished 1948, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 110; see also #132, 150
- Lyon, Samuel E. Cottage "PRINCIPAL FLOOR." ink wash LR (Item 133 recto)
- Lyon, Samuel E. Residence "BASEMENT." watercolor, ink LR (Item 150 recto)
  later moved to 7 Lyon Place, rear addition, 1847; gardener's house, 1851; demolished, 1948, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 110; see also #132-133
- Lyon, William P. Residence (Item 102a verso)
  see also recto and drawing #103 (probably a variant)
- Lyon, William P. Residence "Principal of the Lyon plan." ink MR; "Second story" ink UR (Item 102b)
  probably a variant of drawing #102a
- Lyon, William P. Residence "Study for Wm. P. Lyon." ink wash MR (Item 102a recto)
  see also verso and drawing #103 (probably a variant)
- Mechanics Hall (Item 303a)
  demolished
- Mechanics Hall "Section. Hotel Newark, N.J." ink UR (Item 302)
- Mechanics Hall "First Sketch of a Plan for a Hotel, Newark," ink LC
- Mechanics Hall "FIRST SKECTH OF A PLAN FOR A HOTEL. NEWARK." watercolor LL-LR (Item 303b)
  demolished, see also drawing #303a
- Meeting house, unidentified "Metting house" ink UL (Item 201)
- Merchants' Exchange (Item 306 verso)
  7/28/94 could be same as Commercial Exchange, in case it is would have later, 1862 date, see 301, 307 etc.
- Merchant's Exchange (Item 306 recto)
  7/28/94 could be same as commercial exchange
- Merrick House (Item 084b verso)
- Merrick House (Item 084b recto)
- Merrick House (Item 084a)
- Merrick, Thomas Dwelling "Tyrdyn Terrace" AKA The Terraces "EAst Front. No. 5" ink LC (Item 83)
  extant, much altered
- Merrick, Thomas Dwelling "Tyrdyn Terrace" AKA The Terraces "Attic Story. 4" (Item 083 a.2 verso)
- Merrick, Thomas Dwelling "Tyrdyn Terrace" AKA The Terraces "Second Story. 3" (Item 083 a.2 recto)
- Merrick, Thomas Dwelling "Tyrdyn Terrace" AKA The Terraces "East" (Item 083 b)
- Merrick, Thomas Dwelling "Tyrdyn Terrace" AKA The Terraces "Principal floor. 2 Dwelling for Merrick first study" (Item 083 c)
- Methodist Church, Red Hook "Elevation of Front. by A. J. Davis, Arc't." ink LC (Item 218b)
  framed by Jonathan Beers of Bridgeport, Conn., transported by water and overland, replaced 1893, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 113; see #217-218a
- Middlesex Pauper Lunatic Asylum, London "Middlesex Pauper Lunatic Asylum, London, Eng. Plan and Elevation. To a parallel scale with the N.York Asylum"
  London (England)
- Middlesex Pauper Lunatic Asylum, London "Middlesex Pauper Lunatic Asylum, London, Eng. Plan and Elevation. To a parallel scale with the N.York Asylum"
  duplicate
- Middlesex Pauper Lunatic Asylum, London "Middlesex Pauper Lunatic Asylum, London, Eng. Plan and Elevation. To a parallel scale with the N.York Asylum"
- Monell House "MONELL." ink NC (Item 146)
- Monell House "MONELL." ink NC (Item 146)
- Monument to Pres. Caldwell, University of North Carolina (Item 378 recto)
  Chapel Hill (N.C.)
- Monument to Pres. Caldwell, University of North Carolina (Item 378 verso)
- Moore, A. O. House "A. O. Moore" (Item 88)
- Moore, A. O. House "Study for A. O. Moore - Principal Story" (Item 87)
- Moore, A. O. House "Study for A. O. Moore." (Item 110)
  Wildmont is A. J. Davis summer lodge, built in 1856-1859 (additions 1860s and 1878), burned 1884, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 116-117
- Morris, Richard O. House, Hawkwood "PLANTATION MANSION OF RICHARD O. MORRIS.VA. 1851." watercolor ML-MR (Item 94)
  Virginia
  1851-1854shell extant, severly damaged by fire in 1982, peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 115
- Morse, Samuel F. B. House (Item 155a)
  Poughkeepsie (N.Y.)
  Morse was a painter and an inventer; remodeling, extant, later addition, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 115; see also drawings #155b-d
- Morse, Samuel F. B. House (Item 155b)
  Morse was a painter and an inventer; remodeling, extant, later addition, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 115; see also drawings #155a-d
- Morse, Samuel F. B. House "Principal, or Parlor floor. 2 houses." (Item 155c)
- Morse, Samuel F. B. House "First floor over parlor." graphite LL-LC (Item 155)
  Morse was a painter and an inventer; remodeling, extant, later addition, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 115; see also drawings #155a-c
- Mount Wollaston (Item 249f verso)
  Residence for Charles Francis Adams and John Quincy Adams, many later revisions, not built.
- Mount Wollaston "Wollaston" watercolor, graphite BM (Item 249a)
  House for Charles Francis Adams and John Quincy Adams, many later revisions of design, not built.
- Mount Wollaston (Item 249b)
  House for Charles Francis Adams and John Quincy Adams, many later revisions of design, not built. This image heavily reworked
- Mount Wollaston "IX Transverse Section." watercolor, ink UR (Item 249c)
  Residence for Charles Francis Adams and John Quincy Adams, many later revisions, not built. Upper story of drawing reworked at later date.
- Mount Wollaston "Bay End. VII" ink wash, ink, graphite UR (Item 249)
- Mount Wollaston "Study for Wollaston" watercolor BM (Item 249f recto)
- Mount Wollaston "A Study for Wollaston Principal Floor" (Item 249g recto)
- Mount Wollaston "Study for Wollaston, Sec. Story" watercolor, graphite UM (Item 249g verso)
- Mount Wollaston "Aral 1. First study for Wollaston Hall residence of the John Quincy Adams family by A. J. Davis in 1845" ink graphite UL-UR. (Item 249h recto)
  Residence for Charles Francis Adams and John Quincy Adams, many later revisions, not built. Drawing heavily reworked
- Mount Wollaston "Aral II. Second Floor" watercolor, graphite UM (Item 249h verso)
- Mount Wollaston "Aral III." watercolor graphite UM "Attic" graphite UR (Item 249i)
- Mount Wollaston (Item 574)
  see also drawings #249a-i 252b 370 379; designed for Charles Francis Adams and John Quincy Adams, not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 111
- Mount Wollaston "Massachusetts - Bay Front" (Item 249c)
  Residence for Charles Francis Adams and John Quincy Adams, many later revisions, not built. Roof portion of drawing heavily reworked at later date.
- Mount Wollaston, for Charles Francis Adams and John Quincy Adams "IX. TRANVERSE SECTION." watercolor, ink UR (Item 249e)
  not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 111. Davis erased, altered and enlarged this design, previous design still visible
- Munn, John Residence "Attic, Munn, 4 Utica" ink UR (Item 162)
  Utica (N.Y.)
  extant (now Dowling Nursing Home), veranda partially enclosed, some interior changes, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 116; see also #96, 163, 365
- Munn, John Residence "Second Story" ink UR (Item 163)
  extant (now Dowling Nursing Home), veranda partially enclosed, some interior changes, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 116; see also #96, 162, 365
- Munn, John Villa "Principal Story" ink, UR (Item 365 recto)
  Extant, now Dowling Nursing Home; veranda partially enclosed; some interior changes
- Munn, John Villa [Plan] (Item 365 verso)
- Museum or library "Third Story. Reading & bedrooms. Fourth story Museum 25 by 60. 20 high." (Item 51)
- New Haven Church, Pulpit "Pulpit New Haven Church" graphite, BR (Item 208)
- New York Custom House, publication "CUSTOM HOUSE, NEW YORK DESIGNED BY ITHIEL TOWN AND ALEXANDER JACKSON DAVIS, ARCHITECTS." NA ML-MR (Item [611])
  other artists: John Frazee and others; extant (now Federal Hall Memorial) modified in execution by others, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 107
- New York Geographical Society "House No. 11 29th Street" ink UL (Item 277 verso)
- New York Historical Society "N.Y. His. Soc. F. G. No. 5.6" (Item 047 recto)
  not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson davis, 119; Vail, Knickerbocker Birthday, 119
- New York Historical Society "Study for N.Y. Historical Society Lib. 100 or 130 Ft. Sq." (Item 048 recto)
  not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 119; Vail, Knickerbocker Birthday, 119
- New York Historical Society "Hist. 3 4" (Item 047 verso)
- New York Hotel "Design for a Hotel, N.Y. made 1828, by Alexander Jackson Davis" (Item 18)
- New York Paris Hotel "Apartment House or New York Paris Hotel" (Item 019 recto)
- New York Paris Hotel "Apartment House or New York Paris Hotel" (Item 019 verso)
- New York Post Office "Design made for the Post Office N.Y." (Item 28)
  competition in 1867, Davis's entry not executed, reworked in 1882.
- New York Post Office "Study for the New York Post Office" (Item 027b)
- New York Post Office "Study for the New York Post Office." (Item 027b)
- New York Post Office "Designed for the N.Y. Post Office by A.J.D." (Item 027a)
- New York Post Office "Designed for the N.Y. PostOffice." (Item 29)
  very detailed presentation, competition in 1867, Davis's entry not executed, reworked in 1882.
- New York University "Project for New York University", verso CM graphite (Item 16)
  Published p. 23 "A. J. Davis and American Classicism" 1989 Federal Hall exhibition catalogue. Classical version of NYU.
- North Carolina Hospital for the Insane "Asylum Raleigh" graphite LR (Item 325)
  Hospital undertaken urged by Dorothea Dix, one of Davis's last large commissions, Partially extant, center section demolished, altered, added to.
- North Carolina State Capitol "1831 to 33. Design for N.C. State House" graphite UC (Item 326 recto)
  extant
- Notes on reading, Davis architectural ideas (Item 548 recto)
- Notes on reading, Davis architectural ideas (Item 548 verso)
- Notice of book publishing A. J. Davis's works "Views of Public Buildings, Edifices and Monuments, in the Principal Cities of the United States, correctly drawn on stone by A. J. Davis"
- Office building "For Stores" graphite LR (Item 300 a)
- Office building on Broadway (Item 300 b)
- Office building unidentified (Item 316 a)
  Half of elevation heavily reworked. Watermark: JWhatman
- Office building, Gothic (Item 300 c)
- Office building, unidentified (Item 331)
- Office building, unidentified (Item 334)
- Ohio State Capitol "Davis design Cap. Ohio" (Item 369)
  Columbus (Ohio)
  Unexecuted. Consulted w/ Thomas Cole...revision of competition design.
- Ohio State Capitol "Long Section" ink LC (Item 314 a recto)
- Ohio State Capitol "For State Capitol, Ohio" LR graphite, very faded (Item 314 b verso)
- Ohio State Capitol "Section East & West" UR watercolor (Item 314 c)
- Old Alms House "Old Alms House on Chambers St. N.Y. in 1825" (Item 14)
- Oneida Valley National Bank "Bank at Oneida" ink, UR (Item 318)
  Oneida (N.Y.)
  demolished 1918
- Parson, Charles chapel "Ch Parson Chapel." graphite LC (Item 456)
  see also #465; drawn on the verso of a letter
- Parsonage, University of Virginia "COTTAGE GOTHIC. for Parsonage, University, Va." ink MC (Item 82)
  Charlottesville (Va.)
  pqrtial plan on verso folded to superpose on plan on recto
- Paulding House [Full Size Mullion Details] (Item 251b verso)
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst "Great West wind Paulding" graphite UR (Item 581)
  see #582-590a-g,377; built for Paulding, Mayor of N.Y. (1827-29); extant, Lyndhurst;bought 1880 by J. Gould; Peck,Alexander Jackson Davis,108,118
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst (Item 583)
  see #581-590a-g,377; built for Paulding, Mayor of NY (1827-29);extant, Lyndhurst; bought by Jay Gould in 1880; Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 108, 118
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst (Item 582 recto)
  see #581-590a-g,377; built for Paulding, mayor of N.Y. (1827-29); extant, Lyndhurst;bought 1880 by J. Gould; Peck,Alexander Jackson Davis,108,118
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst (Item 582 verso)
  see #581,590a-g,377; built for Paulding, Mayor of NY (1827-29);extant, Lyndhurst; bought by Jay Gould in 1880; Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 108, 118
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst (Item 584)
  see #581-590a-g,377; built for Paulding, mayor of NY (1827-1829); extant, Lyndhurst; bought 1880 by J. Gould;Peck,Alexander Jackson Davis,108,118
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst "window over door G. Merritt" graphite UL-UC (Item 585)
  see #581-590a-g,377 built for Paulding, mayor of NY (1827-1829); extant, Lyndhurst; bought 1880 by J. Gould;Peck,Alexander Jackson Davis,108,118
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst (Item 586)
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst (Item 587a)
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst "Basement." graphite UR; "Plan D.1." graphite UR (Item 587b)
  see #581-590a-g, 377; built for Paulding, mayor of NY (1827-1829); extant, Lyndhurst; bought 1880 by J.Gould;Peck,Alexander Jackson Davis, 108,118
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst (Item 587c)
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst "Plan, B. 2." ink UL (Item 587)
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst "Principal floor." ink UR; "Plan D.2" ink, graphite UL (Item 587e)
  see #581-590a-g, 377; built for Paulding, mayor of NY (1827-1829); extant, Lyndhurst; bought 1880 by J.Gould;Peck,Alexander Jackson Davis,108,118
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst "Attic." ink UR; "Plan E.3." ink UL (Item 590e)
  see #581-590a-g, 377; built for Paulding, mayor of NY (1827-1829); extant, Lyndhurst; bought 1880 by J.Gould; Peck,Alexander Jackson Davis,108,118
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst "Basement." ink UL; "Plan E.1." ink UR (Item 590)
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst "Principal" ink UR; "Plan E.2." ink UL (Item 590)
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst "Principal floor." graphite UC; "plan F.2" graphite UL (Item 590g recto)
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst "Attic story." graphite UC; "plan F.3." graphite UL (Item 590g verso)
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst (Item 588 recto)
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst (Item 588 verso)
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst (Item 590a)
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst "E. No. 5" graphite UR (Item 590b)
  see #581-590a-g, 377; built for Paulding, mayor of NY (1827-29); extant, Lyndhurst; bought by J.Gould 1880;Peck,Alexander Jackson Davis, 108,118
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst (Item 590c)
- Paulding, William and Philip R. House, Knoll/Merritt, George House, Lyndhurst "Extreme North End." ink LC; "No. 7" graphite UR (Item 589)
- Pauper Lunatic Asylum "Lunatic Asylum elevation of the North End East to West"
  partially built 1837-39; 1847-48, with modifications by others, one octagon extant but damaged by fire
- Pauper Lunatic Asylum "Island Retreat, or Pauper Lunatic Asylum, Blackwell's Island, N.York. Elevation and plan of the principal floor." (Item 31)
  very detailed presentation, partially built 1837-1839; 1847-1848 with modifications by others, one octagon extant but damaged by fire.
- Pauper Lunatic Asylum "Island Retreat, or Pauper Lunatic Asylum, Blackwell's Island, N.York. Elevation and plan of the principal floor."
  duplicate of 31f partially built 1837-39, 1847-48; with modifications by others, one octagon extant but damaged by fire.
- Pauper Lunatic Asylum "Lunatic Asylum elevation of the North End East to West"
  partially built 1837-39; 1847-48, with modifications by others, one octagon extant but damaged by fire, duplicate
- Phelps House (Item 244a)
  Springfield (Mass.)
- Phelps, House "Phelps, with Downing's sketches." ink, graphite UM "Upper Story." ink, graphite UR (Item 244c.2)
  two drawings joined together (244 c.1)
- Phelps, House "First Study for Phelps. see his portfolio and the several albums. Principal floor." ink, graphite UR. (Item 244c.1)
  two drawings joined together
- Phelps, House "Phelps. Second Story. No.3." graphite, ink UR (Item 244b)
- Phillips and Tabor Houses "James W. Phillips _______Tabor." graphite UR (Item 296)
  partial house plans on verso
- Plan, unidentified (Item 239 verso)
- Post office "Post Office" graphite UR (Item 332 verso)
  competition design, not executed, competition in 1867, Davis revised and redrew the design in 1882
- Post Office, Cooper Union "Parallel - Post-Office and Cooper Inst." (Item 26)
  unusual comparison drawing
- Post office, record office or library "Plan for Post Office Record Office or Library" (Item 332 recto)
- Potter House (Item 295)
- Powell, Mrs. House "Second 4. Principal 3. Cellar No 1 Basement 2" ink, graphite throughout (Item 241)
- Presbyterian Church, Chapel Hill "Oratory at Chapel Hill, N.C." ink, LL (Item 324)
  burned 1919
- Probasco House (Item 109)
- Public building "Palmyrean" graphite LR (Item 311)
  watermark: JWhatman 1868
- Public building (Item 307 d)
  probably commercial exchange 7/28/94
- Public building, unidentified "Section showing Interior Construction of Circular Plan" (Item 027c)
- Public building, unidentified "Section Showing Interior Construction of Circular Plan" (Item 027c)
- Public building, unidentified (Item 327)
- Public building, unidentified (Item 329)
- Public building, unidentified (Item 330)
- Public building, unidentified (Item 315)
- Public building, unidentified (Item 316 b)
  Watermark: JWhatman Turkey Mills 1829
- Public building, unidentified (Item 307 c)
  probably commercial exchange, 7/28/94
- Public Buildings in the City of New-York, 1829 (Item 633)
  Scope and Contents
  6 drawings on one sheet, drawn by A.J. Davis and engraved by William D. Smith. Buildings pictured are the Rotunda-Chambers Street; Merchant's Exchange, Wall Street; 2nd Unitarian Church- Mercer c. Prince; Synagogue- Elm Street; U.S. Branch Bank- Wall Street; Masonic Hall- Broadway.
- Public library "Third Plan Public Library" (Item 001b verso)
  see 001b recto; see also #0-10.
- Public library "For A Public Library" ink CM (Item 4)
- Pulpits (Item 239 recto)
- Rathbone, Joel House, "Kenwood" Window Details (Item 251b recto)
- Rathbone, Joel House, Kenwood (Item 113)
  villa demolished, gate lodge extant (remodeled?) and farmhouse possibly extant, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 110
- Rathbone, Joel Villa, Kenwood "first study for Joel Rathbone Albany." ink MR (Item 134a)
  farmhouse, gate lodge, furniture, south of Albany, villa demolished, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 110; see also drawings #113, 134a-h, 135
- Rathbone, Joel Villa, Kenwood "BASEMENT." watercolor, ink UR (Item 134c)
- Rathbone, Joel Villa, Kenwood "SECOND STORY" ink wash, ink UR (Item 134)
- Rathbone, Joel Villa, Kenwood "Joel Rathbone, Albany, West End. 1842." ink LC-LR (Item 134e)
  farmhouse, gate house, furniture, south of Albany, villa demolished, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 110; see also drawings #113, 134a-h, 135
- Rathbone, Joel Villa, Kenwood "House of Joel Rathbone, Esq. Albany, commenced 1842, finished 1846" ink LR (Item 134)
- Rathbone, Joel Villa, Kenwood "NORTH END." watercolor LC (Item 134g)
- Rathbone, Joel Villa, Kenwood (Item 134h)
- Rathbone, Joel Villa, Kenwood, gate lodge "Gate lodge." ink UR (Item 134b)
- Raymond, Robert and Sedgewick, Charles correspondence (Item 367 d recto/verso)
  Syracuse (N.Y.)
- Raymond, Robert R. house Letter (Item 367 c)
- Raymond, Robert R. house [Letter from Raymond to Davis] (Item 367 a recto/verso)
  no evidence of execution
- Raymond, Robert R. house [Letter from Raymond to Davis with sketch plan] (Item 367 b recto/verso)
- Raymond, Robert R. House Notes (Item 367 e recto/verso)
- Raymond, Robert R. house [Letter from Raymond to Davis with sketch plan] (Item 367 b recto/verso)
- Redmond House "Copy of a plan for Redmond" ink LR; "PRINCIPAL FLOOR" ink wash LL-LR (Item 119)
- Redmond Residence "Redmond No.1" (Item 363)
- Residence, unidentified "Specification" ink MC; "South or Entrance front." ink LL; "Upper-story." ink LR (Item 481)
- Residence, unidentified (Item 444)
- Residence, unidentified "A 1." graphite UL (Item 540)
  three-story residence with cellar and basement
- Residence, unidentified "33 ft. DWELLING. STREET FRONT" ink wash, graphite LC (Item 541)
- Residence, unidentified "First floor" ink UL; "South." graphite UC (Item 544)
  for the other half of the plan, see drawing #543
- Residence, unidentified (Item 545)
- Residence, unidentified (Item 543)
  for the other half of the plan, see drawing #544
- Residence, unidentified (Item 546)
- Residence, unidentified "Attic. No. 5. wiyh back room round." graphite UL-UR (Item 547)
- Residence, unidentified "design for a site flanked by wood, and having coach house & stable attached, and retiring behind the trees." ink LR (Item 550)
- Residence, unidentified (Item 567)
  see also drawings #552-553
- Residence, unidentified (Item 566 recto)
- Residence, unidentified "Hunt and Alger" graphite UR (Item 566 verso)
  see also drawing #566;study probably made for more than one project, see Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 112, 113, 114, 115, Hunt's or Alger's houses
- Residence, unidentified [G. W. Penny?] "Principal floor. 2" (Item 246b)
- Residences, unidentified (Item 551 verso)
- Richards, A. C. House, Woodcliff "Principal Story" ink, graphite BR (Item 257)
- Richards, August C. House, "Woodcliff" "Section across the hall, looking South" (Item 38)
  demolished 1939
- Richards, Augustus C. House, Woodcliff "Library.' graphite MC (Item 385)
  built near Fort Tyron site, demolished 1939, Peck, Alexander Jackson Dav8is, 116; see also drawings # 38, 356, 257
- Richmond, Joshua Residence "PRINCIPAL FLOOR" ink LR (Item 100)
  New Bedford (Mass.)
  not identified, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 112
- Roof truss (Item 361 b)
- Roof truss "Truss of roof 2 ft to 1 inch" (Item 361 a)
- Row house, unidentified "CELLARS" ink MC (Item 381)
  "Litch" could refer to Edwin C. Litchfield; see also drawings #411, 382 recto-verso, 383
- Row house, unidentified (Item 429)
- Row house, unidentified "1/4 scale PLAN OF PRINCIPAL FLOOR" ink LC (Item 559)
- Row house, unidentified (Item 561)
  the inscription probably means: mercantile library or opera lot
- Row house, unidentified "PRINCIPAL FLOOR" ink wash, ink LC (Item 562 recto)
- Row house, unidentified (Item 598)
  drawn on verso of a newspaper advertising dated February 1, 1870
- Row house, unidentified "FRONT." ink LC (Item 174)
- Row house, unidentified (Item 538 verso)
- Row house, unidentified "Principal floor. 3." ink, graphite UR (Item 538 recto)
- Ruggles, Samuel B. project for houses and other uses "Mr. Ruggles. lots" graphite LL-ML (Item 428 recto)
  greek revival, not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 110
- Ruggles, Samuel B. project for houses and other uses "Sam. B. Ruggles." graphite UL-ML (Item 428 verso)
  Greek Revival, not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 110
- Rutherford, John House "Principal floor." ink UL (Item 533 recto)
  unidentified, see also drawings #514-516, 526, 531-534
- Rutherford, John House "EAST" graphite LC (Item 532)
  drawn on verso of a contract; unidentified, see also drawings #514-516, 526, 531-534
- Rutherford, John House "Second." graphite UL (Item 533 verso)
- Rutherford, John House "Principal" graphite UL (Item 534)
  unidentified; see also drawings #514-516, 526, 531-533
- Rutherford, John House "Second floor." ink UL (Item 514)
  see also drawings #515, 516, 526, 531-534
- Rutherford, John House "North east." graphite UL; "Garden front Rutherford" graphite LR (Item 515)